Rishbha Jain





PROFILE

Passionate and detail-oriented personnel having 5+ years of experience with the ability to quickly acquire new skills, having the knowledge of the clinical trials and/or life sciences domain. Offering exceptional ability to proactively communicate and collaborate with clients and analyze business needs and provide reporting solution utilizing my analytical skills.



EXPERIENCE

i2e Consulting, Jul 2022 to Present

Spotfire Developer

- Hands on working experience in designing, developing and maintaining complex Spotfire dashboards using features like inform Links (IL), different type of joins, native as well as non-native visualizations.
- Strong ability to understand analytic specifications and translate the specifications into visualizations.

Dataiku Data Engineer

- Strong data analytics skill data cleaning, data wrangling, analyzing data, draw inference and interpreting.
- Exposure to development of digital solutions by understanding the dependencies in different data tables and databases.

Tata Consultancy Services (Indore), Feb 2019 to Jun 2022

SAP BO Developer

- Collaborating with cross-functional development team members for BO4 Reports based on evolving client requirements.
- Collaborating on all stages of report development lifecycle, being a part of an agile scrum team.
 - (Requirement gathering \rightarrow Designing and development of BO4 reports \rightarrow Unit Testing \rightarrow User Acceptance Testing \rightarrow Creating functional specifications \rightarrow Creating user reference guides for production releases \rightarrow Post Go- Live Support as well as Maintenance and Upgrades).
- Reviewing code, debugging problems and correcting issues in order to ensure Test driven development (TDD) of BO4 Reports.
- Worked extensively with Web Intelligence functions, formulas, and variables.
- Applied/Used functions, such as Filters, Conditions, Breaks, Ranking, Sorting, Prompt, Section, Combined queries, Input Controls, Conditional Formatting, Cross Tabs and Charts in Web Intelligence.
- Utilized Merged Dimensions feature to allow linking of two or more data provider (queries).
- Discussing project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.

Validation Analyst

- Worked extensively with Rave Custom Functions and Edit Checks i.e. Study Set Up in RAVE.
- Hands-On Experience in Computerized System Validation (CSV) and testing activities such as Requirement gathering, Risk Assessment, Creation of User and Functional Specifications, Test Objectives and Task & Scenarios Creation along with Test Case execution as per TCS and client's Standard Operating procedures(SOPs) following Regulatory Compliance.
- Logging discrepancies/issues and following up with vendor for resolution and closure.

Support Executive

- Provided Rave-Application Based Support through ServiceNow Tickets and Tasks during day-to-day activities and ad-hoc requests.
- Developed, implemented and/or improved the application production support knowledge management repository(s) to ensure all are documented, process & procedures are clear and periodic reviews are conducted.
- Managed and coordinated hot fixes and maintenance releases.
- Analyzed production issues to determine root cause and provided fix recommendations to the team.
- Supported applications in production. Noted interruptions or bugs in operation and performed problem solving exercise to determine problem and ensure continued use of the application.
- Consulted with users, management, and technical personnel to clarify business issues, identify problems, and suggest changes/solutions.
- Initiated the development, Debugging of Applications/Macros developed using RPA and VBA for Process Automation.
- Reviewing productivity data reports, monthly and weekly status reports for clearing account reconciliation.

Application Used: SAP Business Intelligence, SAP Business Objects, Medidata Rave, Microsoft Office, Visual Basic for Application, Power BI.

Assistant System Engineer- Trainee, Nov 2018 to Feb 2019

Focused majorly on Life Science Domain along with Web Development. Built a project with my scrum team as a Scrum Master.

TECHNICAL SKILLS



- SAP Business Intelligence (BI-BO4).
- Programming Rave Custom Functions and Edit Checks.
- Data Visualization Spotfire, Tableau, Power BI
- Dataiku
- Python
- SQL
- Power Automate
- Visual Basic Application (VBA)

SOFT SKILLS

- Team spirit
- Diligent and adept in multi-tasking
- Optimistic and a big picture thinker





- Performer of the Month November-2022.
- Received two consecutive **A** bands for overall performance at TCS.
- TCS Contextual Master.
- Won TCS 'On the Spot Award' and 'Best Team Award' for delivering 98% First Time Right to the customer.
- Recognized by clients for back-to-back project deliverables with 98% First Time Right to the customer.



- Tableau Desktop Certified Associate by Edureka.
- Rave Study Design and Build Essentials (SDBE).



EDUCATION

Banasthali University, Jaipur (2014-2018)
B. Tech, Electronics and Communication Engineering
Percentage – 81.38%

DAV Public School, Rupnarayanpur, West Bengal Class XII, **Percentage – 85.7%**

DAV Public School, Rupnarayanpur, West Bengal Class X, **CGPA- 8.6**